<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology on SensiMAR</title><link>/categories/technology/</link><description>Recent content in Technology on SensiMAR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interview for Versatilist Podcast</title><link>/post/versatilist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/versatilist/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently invited for an interview in &lt;a href=&#34;https://versatilist.podomatic.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Versatilist&lt;/em&gt; podcast&lt;/a&gt;. I was pleased to participate in this outstanding podcast and to have a great time during this talk. You can listen to it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#39;https://podomatic.com/embed/html5/episode/9595554?autoplay=false&#39; height=&#39;208&#39; width=&#39;504&#39;frameborder=&#39;0&#39; marginheight=&#39;0&#39; marginwidth=&#39;0&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SensiMAR awarded at Conference</title><link>/post/icgi2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/icgi2019/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A publication related to the SensiMAR study was awarded as best communication of young researcher, last November 23 at the conference ICGI 2019. A proposal for designing a multisensory AR app is made and the current article presents some insights included in this awarded communcation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Testing SensiMAR in Conimbriga</title><link>/post/sensimar-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/sensimar-02/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;SensiMAR was out for user tests. In a total of 8 days, Conimbriga&amp;rsquo;s visitors were able to see more, to hear more, and to smell more. The house of Cantaber was augmented with a virtual reconstruction, a soundscape, and a smell of &lt;em&gt;garum&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SensiMAR: The visual Content</title><link>/post/sensimar-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/sensimar-01/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, I have produced visual content to be on display for the SensiMAR experience. This data relates to the reconstruction of one part of the House of Cantaber, from Conimbriga.
This article shows what was reconstructed, and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SensiMAR: The Local of the Experience</title><link>/post/conimbriga-spot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/conimbriga-spot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Where is SensiMAR taking place? Conimbra was a huge Roman city, can you be more specific?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Yes, I can. Let’s explore the House of Cantaber.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Insights of Eurographics 2019 in Genoa</title><link>/post/eurographics2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/eurographics2019/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Between 6 and 10 of May, the Porto Antico of Genoa received the 40th Annual Conference of the European Association for Computer Graphics. Very well known among computer graphics community as a great opportunity to share, learn and explore the latest works and ideas, Eurographics 2019 edition was also the right event to find some interesting topics to bridge with SensiMAR prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to predict people&#39;s intention to use a new technology?</title><link>/post/utaut-hucapp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/utaut-hucapp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When we decide to develop a new technological solution to a new context to better predict the success of it, understand people&amp;rsquo;s behaviour and comprehend their intention to use a given technology is essential. But how to do it? A study using a well known model called UTAUT was conducted to undertsand if this model would fit when augmented reality is suggested among archaeoloical sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multisensory in Cultural Heritage?</title><link>/post/multisen-icgi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/multisen-icgi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The majority of cultural heritage sites are shaped for visual consumption. But we, humans, perceive the world with different senses and in real-time.
Thus, multisensory approaches emerge to prize and enhance users&amp;rsquo; experiences. What stage has been reached these kind of applications?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DinofelisAR: mobile AR for Cultural Heritage</title><link>/post/dinofelis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/dinofelis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For two days, Conimbriga&amp;rsquo;s visitors were able to view, in a 360 degrees angle, a majestic reconstruction of a
Forum from the Roman Era superimposed over its current ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>