<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Acceptance Study on SensiMAR</title><link>/tags/acceptance-study/</link><description>Recent content in Acceptance Study on SensiMAR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/acceptance-study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Discovering Monte Mozinho Castro</title><link>/post/mozinho/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/mozinho/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Classified as a Public Interesting Building since 1948, I had driven to Penafiel to visit Monte Mozinho Castro.
On the Northern region of the Country, this Monte Mozinho Hill Fort, also known as &lt;em&gt;Cidade Morta de Penfield&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;ldquo;dead town of Penafiel&amp;rdquo;),
is one of the great archaeological treasures in Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Miróbriga Ruins</title><link>/post/mirobriga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/mirobriga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My first time in Miróbriga Ruins was to make a presentation related to the use of technologies
among archaeological sites. Me and my colleague Alexandino Gonçalves were kindly invited by the archaeologist José Carlos Quaresma, in 2017.
Back then, I felt in love with the cultural and nature richness of this archaeological site. So I came back, over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>S. Cucufate, I found a cultural treasure</title><link>/post/cucufate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/cucufate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the scope of the accpetance study related to the use of augmented reality in archaeological spaces, I had driven to Alentejo, looking for the Roman ruins of S. Cucufate.
After a long travel, surrounded by Nature and under the sun, a marvelous archaeological site pops out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tróia, garum for everyone!</title><link>/post/troia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/troia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To develop an acceptance study related to the use of augmented reality in archaeological spaces, I had driven to Tróia. I found myself surrounded
by the beauty and quietness of the river estuary, the richness of historical remnants from Roman Empire,
and the friendliness of the staff. What a pleasant stay! Let me tell you about this amazing archaeological site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conimbriga</title><link>/post/conimbriga/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/conimbriga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ancient city of Conimbriga is the largest Roman settlement in Portugal and is well worth visiting on any tour of the
country&amp;rsquo;s central and northern regions. It is classified as a National Monument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>