<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cultural Heritage on SensiMAR</title><link>/tags/cultural-heritage/</link><description>Recent content in Cultural Heritage on SensiMAR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cultural-heritage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>São Cucufate Roman villa - Part 2: Preservation and commentary</title><link>/post/cucufateii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/cucufateii/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This second part presents concluding comments and information related to Preservation and commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>São Cucufate Roman villa - Part 1</title><link>/post/cucufate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/cucufate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Located in the tranquil countryside c.4km to the west of Vidigueira (central Alentejo), the archaeological site of São Cucufate is one of Portugal’s best known Roman villas, boasting well-preserved structural remains and a long history of occupation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conimbriga, the Abandoned City</title><link>/post/conimbriga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/conimbriga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Conimbriga is the largest Roman settlement in Portugal and is well worth visiting on any tour of the
country&amp;rsquo;s central and northern regions. It is classified as a National Monument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more than 100.000 visitors per year, the Roman ruins of Conimbriga are the most important archaeological site in Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multisensory in Cultural Heritage?</title><link>/post/multisen-icgi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/multisen-icgi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The majority of cultural heritage sites are shaped for visual consumption. But we, humans, perceive the world with different senses and in real-time.
Thus, multisensory approaches emerge to prize and enhance users&amp;rsquo; experiences. What stage has been reached these kind of applications?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Miróbriga: Uncovering the Southern Portugal</title><link>/post/mirobriga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/mirobriga/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My first time in Miróbriga Ruins was to make a presentation related to the use of technologies
among archaeological sites. Me and my colleague Alexandino Gonçalves were kindly invited by the archaeologist José Carlos Quaresma, back in 2017.
I felt in love with the cultural and nature richness of this archaeological site at first sight and I came back, over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tróia, Garum for Everyone!</title><link>/post/troia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/troia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To develop an acceptance study related to the use of augmented reality in archaeological spaces, I had driven to Tróia. I found myself surrounded
by the beauty and quietness of the river estuary, the richness of historical remnants from Roman Empire,
and the friendliness of the staff. What a pleasant stay! Let me tell you about this amazing archaeological site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Discovering Monte Mozinho Castro</title><link>/post/mozinho/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/mozinho/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Classified as a Public Interesting Building since 1948, I had driven to Penafiel to visit Monte Mozinho Castro.
On the Northern region of the Country, this Monte Mozinho Hill Fort, also known as &lt;em&gt;Cidade Morta de Penfield&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;ldquo;dead town of Penafiel&amp;rdquo;),
is one of the great archaeological treasures in Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DinofelisAR: mobile AR for Cultural Heritage</title><link>/post/dinofelis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/dinofelis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For two days, Conimbriga&amp;rsquo;s visitors were able to view, in a 360 degrees angle, a majestic reconstruction of a
Forum from the Roman Era superimposed over its current ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>